<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Hector Roux de Bézieux</title>
    <link>/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Hector Roux de Bézieux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the RNA-Seq world</title>
      <link>/project/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/resources/</guid>
      <description>Overview Recently, Philippe Boileau joined the Dudoit lab and I had to think on which resources to point him to so that he could start getting up to speed with on the field. Together, we hence build the following list of interesting material. Those fall into 4 broad (and largely overlapping) categories:
 How to produce data with sequencing How to find, access and pre-process data (including how to use bio-informatics tools) How to analyze the data: statistics How to use all of the above to conduct an analysis (with - of course - a strong emphasis on R tools) How to do all those analyses correctly: reproducible research  I&amp;rsquo;ll therefore try to list resources to help in all subjects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tradeSeq</title>
      <link>/project/tradeseq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/tradeseq/</guid>
      <description>tradeSeq: Trajectory-based differential expression analysis for single-cell sequencing data Work in collaboration with Koen Van den Berge, Kelly Street, Wouter Saelens, Robrecht Cannoodt, Yvan Saeys, Sandrine Dudoit and Lieven Clement
Abstract: Trajectory inference has radically enhanced single-cell RNA-seq research by enabling the study of dynamic changes in gene expression levels during biological processes such as the cell cycle, cell type differentiation, and cellular activation. Downstream of trajectory inference, it is vital to discover genes that are associated with the lineages in the trajectory to illuminate the underlying biological processes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>