<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorials on Hector Roux de Bézieux</title>
    <link>/tags/tutorials/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorials on Hector Roux de Bézieux</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ESCAPE</title>
      <link>/project/national_assemby/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/national_assemby/</guid>
      <description>ESCAPE Easy Single-Cell RNA-sequencing Analyis through a Political Example Single-cell RNA-sequencing (scRNA-seq) is a very potent biological tool used for many applications. A far from exhaustive list would include identifying new cell types, finding differentially expressed (DE) genes, and discovering lineages among cells. To get an overview of the principle, see here.
However, the usual framework might seem a little daunting for beginners and, while many well-crafted tutorials exists, they all share the same idea: use a biological dataset as an example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the RNA-Seq world</title>
      <link>/project/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/resources/</guid>
      <description>Overview Recently, Philippe Boileau joined the Dudoit lab and I had to think on which resources to point him to so that he could start getting up to speed with on the field. Together, we hence build the following list of interesting material. Those fall into 4 broad (and largely overlapping) categories:
 How to produce data with sequencing How to find, access and pre-process data (including how to use bio-informatics tools) How to analyze the data: statistics How to use all of the above to conduct an analysis (with - of course - a strong emphasis on R tools) How to do all those analyses correctly: reproducible research  I&amp;rsquo;ll therefore try to list resources to help in all subjects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>