<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications | Hector Roux de Bézieux</title>
    <link>http://hector-rdb.org/publication/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://hector-rdb.org/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Publications</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 15:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://hector-rdb.org/media/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>http://hector-rdb.org/publication/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical Food Assessment Using a Smartphone App With Continuous Glucose Monitoring Sensors: Proof-of-Concept Study</title>
      <link>http://hector-rdb.org/publication/jmir/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://hector-rdb.org/publication/jmir/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background:&lt;/strong&gt; Novel wearable biosensors, ubiquitous smartphone ownership, and telemedicine are converging to enable new paradigms of clinical research. A new generation of continuous glucose monitoring (CGM) devices provides access to clinical-grade measurement of interstitial glucose levels. Adoption of these sensors has become widespread for the management of type 1 diabetes and is accelerating in type 2 diabetes. In parallel, individuals are adopting health-related smartphone-based apps to monitor and manage care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective:&lt;/strong&gt; We conducted a proof-of-concept study to investigate the potential of collecting robust, annotated, real-time clinical study measures of glucose levels without clinic visits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methods:&lt;/strong&gt; Self-administered meal-tolerance tests were conducted to assess the impact of a proprietary synbiotic medical food on glucose control in a 6-week, double-blind, placebo-controlled, 2×2 cross-over pilot study (n=6). The primary endpoint was incremental glucose measured using Abbott Freestyle Libre CGM devices associated with a smartphone app that provided a visual diet log.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results:&lt;/strong&gt; All subjects completed the study and mastered CGM device usage. Over 40 days, 3000 data points on average per subject were collected across three sensors. No adverse events were recorded, and subjects reported general satisfaction with sensor management, the study product, and the smartphone app, with an average self-reported satisfaction score of 8.25/10. Despite a lack of sufficient power to achieve statistical significance, we demonstrated that we can detect meaningful changes in the postprandial glucose response in real-world settings, pointing to the merits of larger studies in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/strong&gt; We have shown that CGM devices can provide a comprehensive picture of glucose control without clinic visits. CGM device usage in conjunction with our custom smartphone app can lower the participation burden for subjects while reducing study costs, and allows for robust integration of multiple valuable data types with glucose levels remotely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trial Registration:&lt;/strong&gt; ClinicalTrials.gov NCT04424888; &lt;a href=&#34;http://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04424888&#34;&gt;http://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/show/NCT04424888&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding All Significant Closed Connected Subgraphs</title>
      <link>http://hector-rdb.org/publication/mlcb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://hector-rdb.org/publication/mlcb/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving replicability in single-cell RNA-Seq cell type discovery with Dune</title>
      <link>http://hector-rdb.org/publication/dune/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://hector-rdb.org/publication/dune/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multimodal cell census and atlas of the mammalian primary motor cortex</title>
      <link>http://hector-rdb.org/publication/adkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://hector-rdb.org/publication/adkins/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An integrated transcriptomic and epigenomic atlas of mouse primary motor cortex cell types</title>
      <link>http://hector-rdb.org/publication/yao/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://hector-rdb.org/publication/yao/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-neuronal expression of SARS-CoV-2 entry genes in the olfaory system suggests mechanisms underlying COVID-19-associated anosmia</title>
      <link>http://hector-rdb.org/publication/brann/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://hector-rdb.org/publication/brann/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trajectory-based differential expression analysis for single-cell sequencing data</title>
      <link>http://hector-rdb.org/publication/tradeseq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://hector-rdb.org/publication/tradeseq/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influence of pulsatile blood flow on allometry of aortic wall shear stress</title>
      <link>http://hector-rdb.org/publication/aortic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://hector-rdb.org/publication/aortic/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
